Santiago Bustamante García



+57 (300) 330-1001

+1 (217) 288-4765



busta117@gmail.com

(4)

www.santiagobustamante.info

PROFILE

I'm an engineer with several years of experience developing native iOS applications and games. I like working on an startup-style environment with a dynamic team all around the world. I have participated in multiple projects which gave me great experience personally and professionally working both by myself and in a team.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Mobile Director

MedAnswers

Los Angeles, California, USA

Oct 2018 - present

- · iOS team leader
- Android developer
- Setup and maintain CI/CD for testing and store releases, handling 2 different app targets and reducing possible human error
- Reduced deploys time by 30% on the CI/CD
- iOS onboarding security enhanced by implementing phone verification
- Increased iOS app stability by a 60%, decreasing bugs and crash reports
- · Android developer for marketing needs(analytics, deeplink, ads)

iOS Developer TPaga

Medellín, Antioquia, Colombia Oct 2018 - Jan 2019

- iOS team member
- · New features developer
- · Wallet encryption and security enhanced
- Reduced crashes and bugs reports by a 40%
- Implemented CI/CD reducing deploys time by 30%
- Reduced possible human error on deploys by automating the process

Lead iOS Developer Barista Ventures

Medellín, Antioquia, Colombia Apr 2015 - Oct 2018

- iOS team leader
- Released more than 6 apps to the AppStore
- Developed MVPs for US based startups
- Setup CI/CD for each project/client app deployment for test and store
- Improved company development times by developing in-house frameworks

Lead iOS Developer

Periferia IT

Bogotá, DC, Colombia

Apr 2014 - Jun 2015

- · iOS team leader
- Improved the company sales and marketing department by developing some in-house apps
- Supported 1M+ web users into a brand new app for live soccer match tracking
- Developed MVPs for UK based startups

iOS Developer Rokk3r Labs

Bogotá, DC, Colombia

Oct 2014 - May 2015

- Outsourced iOS team member
- Developed MVPs for US based startups
- Helped to increase an US based juices store incomes by creating an app to order and pay products
- Encrypted payments data to prevent frauds
- Started development in swift for iOS apps

iOS Developer KOGI Mobile

Medellín, Antioquia, Colombia Jun 2013 - Apr 2014

- iOS team member
- Developed apps for some colombian enterprises
- Developed MVPs for US based startups
- Increased user engagement by 20% by allowing to watch tv shows by streaming through an app
- Developed in-house frameworks

iOS Developer **GARA Entertainment**

Medellín, Antioquia, Colombia Dec 2011 - Jun 2013

iOS Developer **Doctus LTDA**

Medellín, Antioquia, Colombia Jun 2011 - Dic 2011

Freelance

- iOS team member
- Developed 2D and 2.5D games, using physics and 3D renders
- Reached top 5 in the colombian AppStore with a 2D video game
- Achieved to being 1 of the 2 big regional companies focused only in game development at that time
- · Helped enthusiast game developers in theirs projects by organizing bootcamps and meetups
- iOS team member
- Developed apps for some colombian enterprises
- Improved sales process by developing an in-house app for the sales department

iOS Developer

- Developed navite iOS apps for independent clients
- . Migrated all the taxes process into an official government app for DIAN
- Allowed users to order and pay into some restaurants by developing theirs apps
- Allowed users to play a local radio station via an app
- Allowed users to train for a city marathon, tracking their progress before the event

EDUCATION

EAFIT University (Medellin - Colombia)

System Engineering — 2007-2013

SKILLS

- Swift
- SwitUI
- Kotlin
- Reactive programming
- Xcode
- Gitflow
- Zeplin / Figma

- Objective-C
- **UIKit**
- Realm
- Fastlane CI/DC
- Android Studio
- Memory management and debugging for iOS
- Adobe products (photoshop, illustrator, XD)